Tokyo Mater is a animation, comedy, family film directed by John Lasseter.
A routine tow lands Mater in Tokyo, where he is challenged to a drift-style
race against a nefarious gang leader and his posse of ninjas.
With the help of his friend, 'Dragon' Lightning McQueen, and some special modifications, Mater
attempts to drift to victory and become Tow-ke-O Mater, King of all Drifters.
Mater (voice), played by Larry the Cable Guy.
Lightning McQueen (voice), played by Keith Ferguson.
Tia (voice), played by Elissa Knight.
Guido (voice), played by Guido Quaroni.
Additional Voice Talent (voice), played by Lori Alan.
Additional Voice Talent (voice), played by Mickie McGowan.
Cars Toons is an American animated short series based on the Cars franchise.
It features Lightning McQueen, Mater, and their friends in
comedic antics and adventures canonical to the films.
Larry the Cable Guy reprises his role as Mater while Keith Ferguson replaces Owen Wilson as the voice
of Lightning McQueen until "The Radiator Springs 500 ½", when Wilson reprises his role.
The series premiered on October 27, 2008, with "Rescue Squad
Mater" on Disney Channel, Toon Disney and ABC Family.
Not exclusive to television, the shorts were also released
on home media and/or as theatrical shorts.
The series ended on May 20, 2014, with "The Radiator Springs 500 ½".
The tone is lighthearted.